#### **CURRICULUM VITAE**

ANDREW ANGAYA AMBIA

P.O. Box 2268-50100

Kakamega, Kenya

Mobile: 0713817384/0788375573

Email Address: andrew.ambia@gmail.com

GithHub URL: github.com/Andrew-1000

#### **BIO-DATA**

Birth Date: 6th May 1995

Languages: English & Swahili, all fluent

Nationality: Kenyan Religion: Christian

Gender: Male

Marital Status: Single

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

To be a focused driven person, ready to work against all odds in any environment to deliver quality services individually and as part of a team

#### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

As a devoted IT professional who pursued a Degree in Information Technology from KCA University, I have acquired strong technical skills from my University studies, extensive work experience in diverse fields, personal travel experiences, 3 months attachment at National Social

Security Fund (K) and 6 months internship at ABC Bank. I also possess comprehensive knowledge in the latest IT software and systems, networking with certifications from CISCO and programming (PHP, Android, Java, SQL), all of which are vital in the realization of your company goals. I thrive on the pressures of a fast-paced challenging environment which offers an opportunity for growth and a chance to practically commit my knowledge, skills and experience. I believe in enhancing professionalism, upholding integrity and adhering to the highest standards of ethical responsibilities in all my endeavors through teamwork, creativity and innovation.

# **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

DIAGNOSTIC SKILLS
PROBLEM SOLVING SKILLS
SOFTWARE PROFICIENCY SKILLS

# **EDUCATION BACKGROUND**

2019(November) - 2020(May) MORINGA SCHOOL(SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT)

**2014 - 2018** KCA UNIVERSITY **(BSc I.T)** 

2010 - 2013 ST.IGNATIUS MUKUMU BOYS HIGH SCHOOL

## **PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS**

Certified Cisco Network Associate (CCNA LEVEL 1-4)

KASNEB (CONTINUING CICT)

Linux Fundamentals (KCA UNIVERSITY)

Software Development(Java/Android) (MORINGA SCHOOL)

| Employment History         |   |  |  |  |
|----------------------------|---|--|--|--|
| Date Started               | Business  | Location   | Employer   |  |
|                            | Function  |  |  |  |
| August 11 <sup>th</sup> to |   | Kenya  | KNBS   |  |
| August 31 <sup>st</sup>    | ICT Supervisor  |  |  |  |
| 2019                       |   |  |  |  |
|                            |   |  |  |  |
| January 2019               | Computer  | Kenya  | ANVIO  |  |
| to Date                    | Technician  |  | Enterprise   |  |
|                            |   |  |  |  |
| January 2018               | ICT Support   | Kenya  | ABC Bank   |  |
| to July 2018               |   |  | Group  |  |
|                            |   |  |  |  |
| January 2016               | ICT Support   | Kenya  | NSSF(K)  |  |
| to March                   |   |  |  |  |
| 2016                       |   |  |  |  |
|                            | August 11 <sup>th</sup> to August 31 <sup>st</sup> 2019  January 2019 to Date  January 2018 to July 2018  January 2016 to March | Date Started Business Function  August 11th to August 31st ICT Supervisor 2019  January 2019 Computer to Date Technician  January 2018 ICT Support to July 2018  January 2016 ICT Support to March | Date Started Business Location Function  August 11th to Kenya  August 31st ICT Supervisor 2019  January 2019 Computer Kenya to Date Technician  January 2018 ICT Support Kenya to July 2018  January 2016 ICT Support Kenya to March |  |

#### **Key Responsibilities**

# KENYA NATIONAL BUREAU OF STATISTICS - (11<sup>TH</sup> AUGUST 2019 - 31<sup>ST</sup> AUGUST 2019)

Kenya National Bureau of Statistics is a government parastatal authorized to carry out the 2019 census in accordance with the Statistics Act of 2011. My roles as an ICT Supervisor began before, during and after enumeration in the location assigned to me (Kisa North Location)

The roles involved are:

- Provide technical assistance by responding to technical queries/problems
- Provide account administration support for content supervisors and enumerators
- Coordinating and distributing the ICT Equipments in my assigned location and making sure they are functioning properly.
- Monitoring, management and assessment of CAPI application and mobile device performance and advice accordingly
- Support and ensure proper roll-out and installation of new system updates/versions
- Establish good, professional and courteous relationship with supervisors and enumerators.
- Training of users and the KNBS management in the utilization of the CAPI application in the adherence of Bureau ICT policies and Kenyan security ICT policies
- Escalation of critical system technical issues to the KNBS development team
- Ensure capture of accurate and relevant logging of all requests and incidents raised in the field
- Monitor regional risk posed to the ICT system and device and suggest precautions
- Provide support round the clock during the census period
- Prepare technical reports as needed

#### **ANVIO ENTERPRISE - (February 2019 - Date)**

Anvio Enterprise is a sole proprietor business within Kakamega County mainly dealing with providing I.T goods and services to the public and supply of office stationery & I.T services to private and public institutions in Kenya.

My roles involved:

- Conducting general maintenance of I.T equipments within the organization
- Purchasing I.T goods and services and taking stock records to ensure the

business conforms to accounting standards

- Providing general support of government services to the public through the e-citizen platform
- Managing LAN/WAN to ensure there is internet connectivity at all times
- Administration of the organization's Active Directory
- Keeping track of all transactions made on I.T equipments and services
- Repair and maintenance of computers and all I.T equipments
- Software installation on computers and mobile phones

# ABC BANK GROUP - (January 2018 - July 2018)

The ABC Bank Group comprises of African Banking Corporation(ABC Bank)
Limited, ABC Capital, ABC Insurance and ABC Capital Bank-Uganda. The group
has over three hundred employees

## Position: ICT Support Specialist(Intern)

The role involves supporting the team on matters to do with infrastructure when it comes to

network/hardware upgrade and maintenance. This role also involves support on new technologies and trends on the information communication field in regards to wide area networks and local area networks.

#### The tasks involved:

- Providing general support to countrywide bank Branches
- Provide support to the team in charge of infrastructure projects
- Conducting general maintenance for Information Technology equipment, for
- both hardware and software installations of all system requirements
- Connectivity monitoring throughout the company's LAN/WAN is on par as
- with the technical considerations with service providers
- Providing technical assistance and support related to computer sytems,
- software and hardware through the Information Technology helpdesk System,
- via phone, online and in-person where applicable
- Conducting training on new software and hardware functionalities
- Administration and maintenance of the company's Active Directory and ICT
- inventory
- Conducting software security deployments within the organization
- Administration of Google Apps Email System

#### NSSF(K) JANUARY 2016- MARCH 2016

The National Social Security Fund is a Kenyan government agency responsible for the collection,

safekeeping, responsible investment and distribution of retirement funds of employees in both the formal and informal sectors of the Kenyan Economy The tasks involved:

- Production of members statements as requested using the SSPAS System
- Organization of files in order of registration dates in the filing room
- Registration of new members in the SSPAS
- · Collection and submission of member benefit requests for processing
- Visiting new and existing employers to request for members' registration and
- check whether they comply with monthly payments
- Sales and marketing for the company profile

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Strong**: CSS, HTML, MySQL/MariaDB, Firebase, React, PHP, Java, Javascript **Experience**: Android, Angular.js, Node.js, Linux Operating System

#### **PERSONAL SKILLS**

- 1. Patience and resilience to work with different people
- 2. Teamwork and collaboration skills
- 3. Effective communication skills both written and spoken
- 4. Ability to adapt and learn quickly

#### **HOBBIES**

- 1. Travelling
- 2. Cooking
- 3. Software Programming
- 4. Charity works

# **REFEREES**

| SAMUEL KAMONDAI       | VINCENT KIPKIRUI KEINO | SAMUEL MATENDE       |
|-----------------------|------------------------|----------------------|
| ICT TECHNICIAN        | ACCOUNTANT             | NETWORK              |
| ABC BANK              | NSSF KISUMU            | ADMINISTRATOR        |
| P.O Box 46452 - 00100 | P.O Box 1037 - 40100   | KCA UNIVERSITY       |
| Nairobi, Kenya        | Kisumu, Kenya          | P.O Box 6200 - 00200 |
| 0726848092            | 0720336550             | Nairobi, Kenya       |
|                       |                        | 0722552012           |